aspiringminds.com 2018-04-26

# Privacy Policy | Aspiring Minds

This Privacy Policy (the "Policy") explains how we (Aspiring Minds Inc.) (AM) collect and use personal information that you provide: via our public website www.aspiringminds.com and our member-based websites (which are listed on our public website) (the "Sites"); or offline when participating in any Member Program run by AM. The Policy applies to all Sites and services where the Policy is posted.

This Policy also applies to information we collect from you and/or your employer via our survey tools. Depending on where you are resident, you may be shown a confidentiality notice before participating in a survey. Please note that in cases where the terms of any such survey-specific confidentiality notice conflict with any terms in this Policy, the survey-specific terms will take precedence over the terms in this Policy. 

Please read this Policy before you provide any information to us. By using our Sites, App, survey tools you consent to the collection and use of your information as outlined in this Policy. If you do not agree with the content of this Policy, you should not provide us with any information. 

****
  1. Who We Are

The Sites are owned and operated by Aspiring Minds Inc (AM), which has its principal place of business at 323, Udyog Vihar, Phase 2, Gurgaon, Haryana, India 122016. More information about AM, its subsidiaries and affiliates, and its network of Programs can be found at [www.aspiringminds.com.](http://www.aspiringminds.com/) A full list of AM offices, subsidiaries, and affiliates can be found [here.](http://www.aspiringminds.com/contact-us)

  2. Information We Collect

Information We Collect From You or Your Employer. Information we collect from you or your employer includes your name, business or personal email address, job title, organization, organization’s physical address, direct telephone number, photograph, and biographical details. You also need to provide certain types of information (e.g., email address) to register as a member, submit a question, participate in a survey, or engage in other transactions on our Sites or via App.

Restricted Areas. If you access the Restricted Areas of any of our Sites (via browser or the App), we may collect information about your access to and use of research materials, decision-support tools, and other online and offline resources we offer. 

Information from other sources. We also may periodically obtain information about you from other sources. The collection of such information will be in accordance with applicable privacy laws. Examples of information we receive include updated contact information and additional demographic information. 

Information collected automatically. When you visit the Sites, we automatically collect and analyze certain information about your use of the Sites and the device you used to access the Sites. This information includes your IP address, information about your browser type and language, the date and time you are accessing our Sites, the content of any undeleted cookies that your browser previously accepted from us, and the referring website address. 

Use of cookies and other technologies. We use various technologies to collect information about your activities on our Sites. 

    * _Cookies._ When you visit our Sites, we may assign your computer one or more "cookies." A cookie is a small text file containing information that can we can read later to facilitate your access to our Sites and personalize your online experience. For example, whenever you sign into our Sites, we will record your user ID (and password, if you check the “Save this password for automatic sign in box”) in a cookie on your computer. We may also use cookies to collect information about your activity on our Sites, such as the pages you visit, links you click, and searches you conduct. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies by visiting the Help section of your browser’s toolbar. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use some of the interactive features offered on the Sites.
    * _Other Technologies._ We also use standard Internet technologies, such as web beacons (also called clear GIFs or pixel tags), locally stored objects (often referred to as “flash cookies”) and other similar technologies, to deliver or communicate with cookies and track your use of our Sites. We also include web beacons in e-mail messages or newsletters to track whether you open the messages. We use this information to customize our services and measure the overall effectiveness of our online content, advertising campaigns, and products and services we offer through the Sites. Flash cookies operate differently than browser cookies, and cookie management tools available in a web browser will not remove flash cookies.
    * _Information Collected by Third Parties_ Third parties, such as vendors, advertising entities, and business partners, may use cookies and other technologies described above to collect information about your online activities. The purposes for collecting this information include measuring usage of our Sites and analyzing, modifying, and personalizing content on our Sites. We do not have access to or control over cookies or other features these third parties may use, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Some of these third parties may be third-party network advertisers that offer you the option of not having this information collected.
  3. How We Use Information We Collect

We use the information we collect from and about you for the following purposes, including: 

    * for the purposes for which you provided the information;
    * to respond to your inquiries and to determine which Products and services will help you achieve your business goals; 
    * to attribute content that you make available through the Sites;
    * to communicate with you about surveys, marketing, promotions, executive-oriented events, educational forums, and other exclusive opportunities offered by AM;
    * to customize the content you see; 
    * to engage in research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our Programs, products, and services, as well as develop new products and services;
    * to enforce the legal terms that govern your use of the Sites; and
    * to ensure the technical functioning of the Sites. 

Discussions: In the event that you post information in discussion forums or other areas of the Sites allowing users to upload or post content, please note that this information can be viewed by any user with access to those areas. 

  4. Choices About Use of Your Information

We believe that it is important to give you choices about the use of your information. We will use your information as described in this Policy or any service-specific privacy or data protection notice. If we want to use your information for a purpose not described in this Policy, we will first obtain your consent to do so. 

_Marketing Communications_ : We will respect your wishes not to receive, or to stop receiving, marketing communications. You can change your marketing preferences by contacting us as described below. If you provided us with your email address in order to receive such communications, you can opt out at any time by using the unsubscribe links or instructions at the bottom of our emails. Please note that we will continue to send you service-related communications regardless of any such request. We will not share or sell your information and personal details with third parties (for the avoidance of doubt, other than subsidiaries and/or affiliates) for their own promotional or marketing purposes unless you give us consent to do so and where permitted by applicable law.

  5. Disclosure of Information

Utilization information. We may share information with our organizational Members about how their employees use the Sites and the resources available to them through the Sites (e.g. how employees used certain features of the Sites, utilization trends, which features were most popular with the Member’s employees.) 

We may share your information with third-party companies or individuals in the following instances: 

    * When we engage service providers and third-party agents to process personal information on our behalf. When we do so, we contractually require these service providers to implement adequate security and privacy measures to ensure that your personal information will be appropriately protected and only used for the purposes of performing the services for us.
    * In response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process (including for national security and law enforcement purposes); to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
    * When we believe it is appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the justified rights, property, or safety of AM, our customers, or others; and in connection with our Terms of Service and other agreements.
    * In connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, including any pre-transaction diligence, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

We also may share aggregate or anonymous information with third parties, including advertisers, investors, and partners. Aggregate or anonymous information does not contain any personal information and its use and disclosure is not subject to the terms of this Policy.

  6. International Transfers of Your Information

We operate the Sites in India and, depending on your country of residence, the submission of information to our Sites may involve its transfer to our offices in various countries for certain processing operations. You should be aware that privacy laws in these countries may not provide protections equivalent to those of your country of residence.

All AM entities have the same technical, physical, and administrative security controls and are required to comply with our data protection policies and procedures, applicable laws, and the terms of our client and member contracts governing the collection and use of information.

  7. Access to Your Information

In some cases, you may directly access your online profiles and other personal details, and amend, update or add information yourself at any time by logging into your account.

You may request access to any certain information that we hold about you, ask us to correct certain information which may be inaccurate, and/or ask us to block or delete such information and object to the processing of personal data except where the law requires otherwise. Please note that in cases where your employer is the Data Controller of such information, we will need to obtain their permission before making such changes. 

We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide you with any services which you request. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

  8. Information Security

We have implemented reasonable technical and organizational security measures to help protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure, or destruction of information. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be entirely secure, and we cannot and do not guarantee or warrant the security of any information that you transmit on or through our website or App or that we otherwise maintain. 

We make reasonable efforts to restrict access to information to only those employees, contractors, and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop, or improve our Programs, products, and services, and consistent with the level of sensitivity of such data. We subject our third-party agents to contractual controls to ensure that they appropriately protect and use the information they access or receive from us. 

Please note that the effective security with respect to our Sites depends, in part, on you ensuring that any IDs and passwords that you have been issued by us are kept confidential and secure and that you adhere to the restrictions on password and ID-sharing set forth in our Terms of Service. 

  9. Other Websites

To provide increased value to you, we may provide links to other websites or resources that are not part of the network of Programs, products, or services run by AM or its subsidiaries. We do not exercise control over these websites or their privacy practices, and any information you provide to those sites is subject to the Privacy Policies of those sites and not this Policy.

  10. Children

Our Sites contain business-related content and are specifically aimed at and designed for use by adults. We do not knowingly solicit or collect personal information from or about individuals under the age of 18 years.

  11. Changes to This Policy

This Policy may change from time to time. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will post any Policy changes on this page. Where we make any material changes to this Policy, we will provide a more prominent notice. Your continued use of our Sites following such posts or notices will signal your acceptance of such changes.
